<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybernetics on CFIM360°</title><link>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/</link><description>Recent content in Cybernetics on CFIM360°</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cognitive Cybernetics</title><link>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/cognitive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/cognitive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="identity"&gt;Identity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognitive Cybernetics defines the control architecture that governs cognition as a regulated system rather than a reasoning narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It treats cognition as &lt;strong&gt;signal processing under constraint,&lt;/strong&gt; not as intelligence, thought, or awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="purpose"&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of Cognitive Cybernetics is to formalize how inference, decision-making, and internal representations are stabilized or destabilized over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain does not attempt to improve thinking.
It defines how thinking &lt;strong&gt;breaks, loops, locks, or recovers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Emotional Cybernetics</title><link>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/emotional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/emotional/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="identity"&gt;Identity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emotional Cybernetics defines the control architecture that governs emotional signal regulation under real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not describe emotions as experiences, expressions, or narratives.
It describes them as &lt;strong&gt;regulated signals within a bounded system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="purpose"&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of Emotional Cybernetics is not to explain emotion, but to define how emotional states are &lt;strong&gt;stabilized, amplified, damped, or allowed to collapse&lt;/strong&gt; within a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain exists to formalize regulation, not meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Integrative Cybernetics</title><link>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/integrative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/integrative/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="identity"&gt;Identity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrative Cybernetics defines the control architecture governing &lt;strong&gt;coupling, coordination, and synchronization&lt;/strong&gt; across emotional, cognitive, and somatic cybernetic layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It treats integration as &lt;strong&gt;system behavior,&lt;/strong&gt; not synthesis of meanings or experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="purpose"&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of Integrative Cybernetics is to formalize how multiple regulatory layers &lt;strong&gt;interact without collapse,&lt;/strong&gt; and how coherence is maintained or lost under load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not unify disciplines.
It regulates &lt;strong&gt;interaction dynamics.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="domain-of-governance"&gt;Domain of Governance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrative Cybernetics governs:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Somatic Cybernetics</title><link>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/somatic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfim360.com/cybernetics/somatic/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="identity"&gt;Identity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somatic Cybernetics defines the control architecture that governs physiological regulation as a constraint system for intelligence and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It treats the body as a &lt;strong&gt;regulatory substrate,&lt;/strong&gt; not as a signal source for interpretation or meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="purpose"&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of Somatic Cybernetics is to formalize how bodily states constrain, modulate, and limit system behavior under real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not attempt to improve health or performance.
It defines how regulation &lt;strong&gt;fails, saturates, compensates, or stabilizes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>